Hello, and welcome to Lesson 30 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，这里是 Wolfram U的微积分入门，第30课
The topic for this lesson is volumes by cylindrical shells.
本次课程的主题是 柱壳法求体积
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
先简单回顾一下上节课
In the previous lesson, we learned about the disk and washer methods
在上一课中 我们学了圆盘法和垫圈法
for finding the volumes of solids.
来计算固体体积
As an example of the disk method,
作为圆盘法的示例
let’s say you have the function f[x] = x^2
假设有函数 f[x] = x^2
and you rotate that around the x axis from 1 to 4.
绕 x 轴旋转后在 1 到 4 之间
You get a solid of this type.
可以得到这种图形
To find the volume, what you do is you break up the solid into disks,
要算体积 你需要将他分解为圆盘
and each disk then has a radius of x^2, the value of f[x],
每一个圆盘的半径是 x^2 就是 f[x] 的值
so the area of this disk is πr^2 times, of course, the height,
所以这个圆盘的面积 πr^2 乘这个 高
which is the infinitesimal volume.
就是这个有限部分的体积
Then you get the integral of that giving you the volume of the solid.
然后积分算出来这个固体的体积
The washer method is very simple and similar
垫圈法也一样很简单
because all you do is instead of working with one disk,
因为你要做的就是不是只用一个圆盘而是
you simply subtract the volume of two disks, the outer and inner.
很简单的减去两个圆盘的面积 外圈盘和内圆盘
Basically it works on washers or rings or annuli
基本上 他适用于 垫圈 环 或着 奥利奥
or whatever you call them.
或者随你怎么叫
Now a slightly harder example.
现在有一个稍麻烦一点的例子
Suppose you have the function shown over here
假设有一个这里的函数
and you want to revolve it around the y axis, not the x axis.
你想绕 y 轴转 而不是 x 轴
Then it’s not clear what one means by the inner and outer radii.
那么内径和外径就不清楚了
The goal of this lesson is to talk about
这节课的目标就是讨论
the so-called cylindrical shell method
所谓的柱壳法
which makes this example and similar examples very simple.
会使得这个示例和类似示例非常简单
Let’s build some intuition for the method.
我们先建立一些直觉认识
Let’s say you want to find the volume of the solid.
假设要求固体的体积
You break it into pieces, but these pieces
将他打碎 但这些碎片
are now going to be shells rather than cross sections.
现在是个壳 而不是截面
Because each cell looks like a cylinder,
因为每个微元都像一个圆桶
it’s called the cylindrical shell method.
就被称为 柱壳法
Here’s a typical cylinder.
这里有一个圆桶
It’s very thin.
他非常薄
It has an outer radius of r2 and an inner radius of r1,
他的外半径是 r2 内半径 r1
so that is the difference in the volumes of outer and inner,
因此外部和内部有个体积差
which will give you the volume of that thin shell.
这就是薄壳的体积
If you factor it a little bit, you could rewrite it as
如果稍微考虑一下 可以将其重写为
2πh times the average of r1 and r2
2πh 乘 r1 和 r2 的均值
times the difference between r1 and r2 like over here.
乘 r1 和 r2 的差 像这里
Now because it’s very thin, you can let r2 approach r1,
现在因为他非常薄 我们用 r2 近似 r1
in which case the difference over here becomes dr
这里的差就变为 dr
and the average becomes just r1.
均值就是 r1
Now because you only have one r left, you might as well call it r.
现在就剩一个 r 就将它记为 r
The volume now becomes 2πhrdr.
体积就变为 2πhrdr
The question is what’s h?
问题是 h 是多少
Well, h is the value of the function f as a function of r.
好吧 h 是函数 f 的值 是 r 的函数
The height h becomes now f[r],
高 h 就变为 f[r]
so you have a very nice, simple formula for the volume
所以就有一个非常好的 简单的体积公式
by the method of cylindrical shells.
通过 柱壳法
To go back to our example from the introduction,
回到介绍中我们的示例
you have this function, f[x] = 4x^3 – x^4.
函数为 f[x] = 4x^3 – x^4
You want to work out the volume, so you simply do 2πr
想算体积 只需简单的用 2πr
times the value of the function over here times dr.
乘 这里的函数值 乘 dr
You work it out with Integrate, and you get back the result.
算个积分 就能得到答案
Okay. Now the question is which method should you use,
好 现在的问题是应该使用哪种方法
the washer or disk method or the cylindrical shell method?
垫圈法 圆盘法 还是 柱壳法？
Let’s say here’s an example in which you have two curves,
来看这个示例 有两条曲线
x^2 and x^3, but you want to revolve it around the y axis.
x^2 和 x^3 但是你想他绕 y 轴旋转
With the washer method, you could rewrite things
由垫圈法 可以改写这件事
as cube roots and square roots and get the answer,
为立方根和平方根并且得到答案
but in this case, it’s much simpler
但是这个例子里 会更简单
to simply work with the cylindrical shell method,
要是简单的用一下柱壳法
and you get back the same result.
就能得到同样的答案
You do get the same answer, but the question is which one to use.
你确实得到了一样的答案 但是问题在于用什么方法算
That’s up to you, but typically, the cylindrical shell method
这取决于你 但通常 柱壳法
works well when the axis of the cylinder
效果很好 当圆柱的轴
is the same as the rotation axis.
和旋转轴相同时
Okay. Some minor variations.
好 小小改一下
Let’s say you have a function like over here,
假设有这样一个函数
and you want to rotate it around the line x = 6
你想让他绕直线 x = 6 旋转
rather than the y axis, let’s say.
而不是 y 轴
Then what you do first of all is you find the radius.
然后首先要做的就是找到半径
Keep in mind that the radius is now going to be 6 – x
记住 现在半径是 6 – x
because you are counting from x = 6, so that’s the radius.
因为你是从 x = 6 开始算的 所以这是半径
You have 2π times radius times function value,
用 2π 乘 半径 乘 函数值
and you get back the answer with the cylindrical shell method.
用柱壳法得到答案
On the other hand, if you have a negative axis,
另一方面如果是 负轴
so let’s say you have x = –1 over here, and you have this function.
来看这里 x = –1 有这些函数
Now if you if you look at the radius, it’s going to be x + 1.
现在要是算半径的话 将是 x + 1
Your formula is slightly different.
公式略有不同
You have 2π(x + 1)f[x]dx.
是 2π(x + 1)f[x]dx
You work out the answer, and you get back the volume in this case.
算出答案 得到了这个时候的体积
We spoke a little earlier about comparing the two methods,
我们之前谈到了比较这两种方法，
washer/disk and cylinder.
垫圈/圆盘 和 柱壳
Let’s take an example
来看个例子
where the disk or washer method works a little better.
圆盘或垫圈方法效果更好一点
Let’s say you have f[x] = CubeRoot[x].
假设 f[x] = CubeRoot[x]
You now revolve around the x axis from 0 to 1.
绕 x 轴旋转 在 0 和 1 之间
If you try the cylindrical shell method, things become a bit harder
如果尝试使用柱壳法 事情会变得有点困难
because now the shell height is horizontal rather than vertical.
因为现在壳的高度是水平的 而不是垂直的
If you had to apply the cylindrical shell method,
如果必须用柱壳法
you would first of all rewrite the function as a function of y,
首先要将函数改写为 y 的函数
then work out the shell radius, then work out the integral.
然后计算出壳半径 然后计算出积分
But with the disk method, things are much simpler
但是使用圆盘法 事情要简单得多
because you simply have the cube root of x as the function,
因为只是将 x 的立方根作为函数
so you apply π times r^2dx, integrate from 0 to 1
所以你因该用 π 乘 r^2dx 再从 0 到 1 积分
and you get back the same volume.
得相同的答案
In general, both these methods—
一般而言 这两个办法
the cylindrical shell method and the washer/disk method—
柱壳法 和 垫圈/圆盘法——
have advantages and disadvantages,
有优点有缺点
and you must decide which one is better suited for your problem.
你必须决定用哪一个更适合解决问题
Okay. That brings me to the end of the lesson.
好 本节课就上到这儿了
Basically, what we’ve learned is that the cylindrical shell method
基本上我们学习了柱壳法
is another nice way of finding the volume of solids.
是另一种求固体体积的方法
This method works by breaking up the solid into cylindrical shells.
此方法通过将固体分解为柱壳来算
Those shells are very, very thin, and the height of the shell
这些柱壳非常薄 并且壳的高度
is the value of the function.
是函数值
Sometimes you’ll find that the cylindrical shell method
有时会发现圆柱壳法
is much easier, and it can be very cumbersome or even impossible
更容易 而且可能非常麻烦甚至不可能
to apply the disk/washer method.
应用圆盘/垫圈法
But other times, you might find that the disk/washer method
但有时 可能会发现圆盘/垫圈法
is a lot easier to understand and use, so you might prefer that.
易于理解和使用 因此你可能更喜欢这种方法
Just to review the formulae for the lesson,
回顾一下本节课的公式
first of all if you revolve around the line x = x0
首先 如果绕线 x = x0 旋转
where x0 is positive, then you get x0 – x as the radius,
其中 x0 为正 那么得半径为 x0 – x
so think back to the example involving 6 – x.
请回想一下涉及  6 – x 的示例
On the other hand, if you have a negative or 0 value for x0,
另一方面 如果 x0 的值为 负 或 0
then you’ll have x – x0 over here, so think back to the example
那么这里有 x – x0 回想一下例子
which had an x + 1, which really was an x minus –1.
有 x + 1 的那个 实际上就是 x 减 –1
Those two very simple formulae tell you what you need to do
这两个非常简单的公式告诉你需要做什么
for the cylindrical shell method,
对于柱壳法
and that makes it a very simple method wherever it works.
无论怎么做 他都是非常简单的方法
In the next lesson, we’ll talk about
下节课 我们将讨论
the average value of a function with integration,
积分下函数的均值
but before doing that, do review today’s lesson.
在此之前 请复习今天的课程
It’s a very important lesson.
这节课非常重要
It tells you how to find the volumes of very difficult-looking solids,
它告诉你如何计算看起来非常困难的固体的体积
and it really shows you how powerful calculus is.
它确实展示了微积分的强大
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
本节课到此为止，再见